Gauray Kumar Prince



gkumar475@gmail.com



+919031680803



linkedin.com/in/gaurav-kumar-prince

Summary

I'm a Fullstack Software Developer with a Software Development experience of 6+ years having acquired the Master of Computer Applications from SASTRA University, Thanjavur. I have comprehensive knowledge in Planning, Designing, and developing the solution as per the requirement.

- Web Technologies HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Angular
- Cloud technology Microsoft Azure
- · Tools Git/Github, npm, Jenkins
- REST API, Agile Development,
- CI/CD & DevOps
- · Apache NiFi

Experience



\Re Software Engineer

GE

Jul 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Currently, I'm part of the Thread Connect Engineering team responsible for managing and developing the on-prem as well as a cloud solution.

- Responsible for upgrading the Thread Connect product along with Thread Connect Registry.
- Responsible for implementing CVE Fixes in Thread Connect Product and verifying the fix through OSS
- Improved the existing documentation to help onboard new team members.
- Present demos at the end of sprints.

Information Technology Analyst

Tata Consultancy Services

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022 (7 months)

- Worked as a Developer to support the cloud based solution in live environment.
- Responsible for the deployment of the code to higher environments as and when required.
- Provided multiple training sessions on specific work areas to colleagues.
- Awarded with the Special Initiative Award.



System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Jul 2020 - Dec 2021 (1 year 6 months)

Continue to work as the Developer along with additional responsibilities.

- Worked as a Developer to continue building the cloud-based solution.
- Responsible for the deployment of the code to higher environments as and when required.

- Provided multiple training sessions on specific work areas to colleagues.
- Awarded with the Service and Commitment Award.
- Awarded with the Special Initiative Award.

Assistant System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Jul 2019 - Jul 2020 (1 year 1 month)

I was working as a Node JS Developer for this period for another utility domain client for TCS.

- The project was about building the solution which was to upgrade the existing On-premise system with a Cloud-based solution hosted in Azure Kubernetes System.
- I worked as a Developer to create multiple REST API endpoints in NodeJS.
- Awarded with the On the spot award between this period.
- Also recognized by the client in the weekly newsletters.



Graduate Trainee

Tata Consultancy Services

Jan 2018 - Jul 2019 (1 year 7 months)

Upon completion of the training period in Ignite, I was allocated to a Utilities (Energy) project where my role was as an analyst I was working with analyzing the application and providing test scenarios.

- Helped to create automated test scripts to reduce manual efforts by 70%.
- Also, helped with preparing Daily and Weekly Status Reports for the customer.
- Awarded the Learning Achievement Award twice for completion of multiple training on PL/SQL.
- · Awarded with the On the Spot award twice during this period for the work done with regards to Automation and Analysis of the System.
- Recognized by the Customer for the completion of the Automation and Analysis of the system.



Graduate Trainee

Tata Consultancy Services

Jul 2017 - Dec 2017 (6 months)

Started the IT journey with TCS as a Graduate Trainee. It involved a lot of learning. The training included Technologies like Java, Javascript, Angular, etc. along with the data structure and algorithms. It was also to develop professional proficiency in technologies and personality.

Education



Shanmugha Arts, Science, Technology & Reserch Academy (SASTRA),

Thanjavur

Master of Computer Applications - MCA, Computer Science

2017 - 2020

Completed the MCA from SASTRA University with distinction scoring 8.0069 CGPA.



Ranchi university

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science

2014 - 2017

Completed the B.Sc.(CA) from Ranchi University with 67.17% along with 2 Internships and a project.

Surendranath centenary school ranchi

12th, Science

2012 - 2014

Passed 12th with 72.2% in Science(Physics, Chemistry, Maths).

St. Aloysius high school, Ranchi

10th

2011 - 2012

Completed the 10th from State Board(JAC) with 76%.

Licenses & Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals - Microsoft

Skills

JavaScript • Node.js • Microsoft Azure • Azure Databricks • Angular • Apache NiFi • Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • SQL

Honors & Awards

Service & Commitment Award - Tata Consultancy Services

Jul 2021

Awarded the Service & Commitment award for 3 years of dedicated service.

Special Initiative Award - Tata Consultancy Services

Dec 2021

Received Special Initiative Award for helping with Go Live for the world's first 5-Minute Settlement Solution.

Special Initiative Award - Tata Consultancy Services

Jan 2021

On the Spot Award - Tata Consultancy Services

Feb 2020

On the Spot Award - Tata Consultancy Services

Aug 2019

On the Spot Award - Tata Consultancy Services

Sep 2018

Received On the Spot Award for contributing to the Project.